[no speech detected]
OK, I'm welcome.
Welcome to this class.
I'm on CSA 473 S?
An introduction to computer networks. Now, I'm not sure if everybody
has their cameras off or. I don't see many faces here.
Most of the faces are. Expected here, not here.
At least I want to experiment this time with all the we have had the
cameras on in all our previous courses, but we never had 70 students in one course so.
So maybe maybe it will be difficult to see 70 faces,
but I still want to see everyone. And dumb.
I want to see your reaction because that
is how I change my speed change my phone,
change my top. And right now I think
maybe I'm limited to 25.
Let's see five 5 * 525 on one screen.
And.
25 on other steam.
And and and about 25 people have not done.
[no speech detected]
Alright, you are muted. Yeah yeah I. I don't know if anything is.
Maybe zoom is in. Did you hear the in the beginning
part of it? Honey, yes. Did you hear the beginning part of it?
Yes, yes we did. OK, all right I. I think Zoom is probably not
capable of showing all the faces.
And so while I was going
through all the phases, it.
It kind of crashed and I'm. And then came back.
But I don't see my screen anymore, so let me see what happened to my screen.
OK, my screen is there. And dumb.
It's not shared. Let me see
what happened with shared part. If not shared, shared.
Screen through share. Now let's finish shared. OK,
so I so it's it's quite possible that it is.
It is not possible to see every face OK, but.
While giving a lecture, it's really. Good for the teacher or the instructor to
get a feedback which comes continuously.
By looking at people's faces.
OK, that's a very important feedback.
So as many of you as them, and I think what zoom is probably doing is it is rotating.
I don't know what it is doing, but basically I see only 25 faces and then the other 25 faces are
in the next screen and the next screen I have to press them buttons.
But let's continue. So thank you for.
Coming to this class. One of my computers is still coming up. It decided to change the BIOS
light at the last minute, so let me just see 0613.
Right? And.
[no speech detected]
mix
OK, so welcome. We have 71 people.
I think if five days, four or five days there are 65 students, 66 students,
which is probably the registration. So welcome to this class and 473 and
all of you have asked questions and there are plenty of questions so we
will be busy for the next one hour. And that's the beauty of flipping
the class that most of you already know what I wanted to talk about. But there are so many questions
that cannot could not have been answered in a physical class in
a regular class unflipped class. OK, so I'm going to move on to the
first slide where there is a question.
[no speech detected]
OK, so this is slide #3 and the question is how are all fields
related to each other only through networks or by other means as well? Does one impact the other?
So I listed all these fields here that depend upon computer networking.
And none of these would have been possible if there was no networking.
And so one enables the other distributed computing as possible by networking and
with distributed computing came big data and then clear cloud computing and all that.
So there is a lot of interrelationship.
But at the base of all this is not working. Which network based areas of
computing make the most money? Now the money making part is not only the technology.
There are marketing issues, there are company issues, their management issues.
And all that. OK, and so right now the company
that is making the most money in
the world number one is Apple. And you know what they sell?
They sell networking communication OK,
they sell phones that do Internet. OK, now there are a lot of other companies that do the same thing,
but they don't make that much money. So there are so many issues. But in spite of all that.
They are and they make money only when they sold networking before that.
In the Mac business they never made money they last month.
Alright, now you can still ask questions and I'm monitoring the chat box.
So you can ask the question in the chat box.
And and everyone is allowed to
even unmute and ask. And dumb.
OK. Alright, so. Next slide.
What are some examples of networking related
job roles that some would apply for? Well, my favorite job would be in networking professor.
Of course. And then the next one is networking researcher.
Networking administrator data center support in the data center you need lot of people.
Lot of people who need to know networking. Cloud computing cloud basically
anything to do with the cloud. They need lot of people who need networking and if we want
to do nothing sit in your home. You can write an app. Delighted to network if you are write
an app you need to know networking OK in addition to learning programming.
But lot of people are making money that way. OK, so. So networking is there.
I mean you I I don't know if you can write networking without no, but you can write much of the
computing you can do without knowing how TCP IP works or how you connect
from one computer to the next. Or you know what is an IP address.
And then you know what is the difference between Ethernet and Internet.
If you don't know these things, I don't know. You can go very far,
so this is basic fundamental knowledge today.
[no speech detected]
Next question. And this is on Slide 5. And I'm saying it's slide numbers
because oftentimes zoom. Zoom has bugs
and it will not move this slides, so if I if if you're not on the Slide 5, then you can let me know.
So the slide #5 is the Ethereum built on Ethernet.
Any relationship between them. So Ethernet is different than Internet. OK I will. That will become
clearer in this second lecture. But right now I'm going to use word Internet.
All cryptocurrencies are possible, but only because of the Internet.
Right, in fact, everything that is virtual today is possible because of the Internet.
Without Internet there is no virtual thing.
OK, virtual shopping, virtual education. Virtual currency.
Virtual travel virtual classes, nothing. Everything, the word virtual means Internet based.
OK, what do you think are the limitations
of the current network paradigm? The software, hardware limit politics
are and how can we breakthrough them? Well, that's a very generic question,
and all of the above are issues. OK, and basically the way it works is that there are issues in this
software that issue in the hardware that issue in the development that
issues in the marketing that issues and everybody picks up the issues that their best qualified for.
OK. So everybody picks up the issues
and they make the they make the change the world in that direction,
and so they make they benefit from it. The world benefits from them.
It's a two way St and so if you are a hardware person you can change.
There are lots of issues in networking. If you're a software person,
there's lots of issues in networking. If your systems person there are lots of issues there OK,
and you have a political person. There are lots of issues there too. OK, today in the frontline news,
the airlines. And the phone companies are fighting,
you know, for what? Anybody?
That's a networking issue. OK, and we talk about those issues. Actually exactly those issues,
interference issues and all that in our networking wireless networking course.
So there are three of Valentine's. Why did we use the word adopt during your lecture?
It sounds like a passive world. Why can't a company invent new paradigm
only to adopt but only to adapt to it?
Yes, you can invent a new paradigm. And and and most people
will basically adapt to it. So one company invented Internet.
I actually one university invented Internet. Or maybe a group of universities in invented Internet?
I mean the Internet was. I mean I, we'll go through that history at some point,
but most people just join the stream, join the, join the flow.
[no speech detected]
OK. So. So majority of the world just joined the flow. Now here's the thing.
If you are in a company and I've had company of my own, when you have
your company you have to change. You have to change every day.
You have to see where the world is going. If you don't change you will find
yourself out of date and the company that I was working for a big company,
Digital Equipment Corporation went out of business because they could not adapt or they could
not change when the PC came. They were in the mini computer business
and they changed the whole world from big computers to minicomputers,
but then they could not change the same person who is the president of my company.
He could not change. He could not imagine that everybody will have a computer on their desk.
Why there is a need for a computer on the desk?
Right? So, so The thing is, if you don't adapt you, you die.
This is true for the companies. For academics it is less true. I will tell you what I know.
Lot of professors who have not changed anything in the last 40 years because they just know whatever
they know and they just keep you know digging more deeper in that.
So I'm only half an academic. Alright,
and so I will tell you that basically, even the academics have to adopt.
I have to change every year my field changes. I'm a networking person,
but if you see my team how much networking they know they know a lot of networking,
but they know a lot of AI. They know a lot of blockchain. They know a lot about other things.
Whatever is hot, we have to combine.
[no speech detected]
OK alright. So that was the point.
Next slide on 76.
So their hype cycle here and this is 2019. I will show you 2022 at the end.
And by the way, this changes slides will also be uploaded today, so you will see them.
But basically this one was more interesting than 22 because it has many
things that you already know about now.
Alright, so it says are there technologies that are vital, but since they don't bear economic
interest that's don't get funding from VC. And the answer is yes. If it is not money making this
is will not go there and those things are mostly in Africa.
Are less developed world. Where there is no Internet and we need Internet.
They need Internet, but who will? Who will provide them the Internet? So some humanitarian societies
have to work on those, and they're working on those.
Alright, so yes, like any other field,
there are areas that are not money making,
but they are still good. Still worthy
how could be involved? How can we? How could we get involved in these hot topics as a student
or worker in the industry? Or how to improve our self after graduation? Now here's the mantra.
You got to change every year.
You got to change every year. You got to find out where the world is going and and lead it.
There lead lead us there. If you are, if you if you if you are not
looking then you will be left behind in my day is when I was growing up. The world used to change
in four 5-10 years right? If you should take three months to find a paper, if I want to read a paper,
you know I have to go through lots of correspondence with the author this dad and say he wrote,
wrote a paper, send it to me. And millions to take three weeks to get it there.
Right now I can find a paper in zefi and you know. And and and The thing is,
the world is changing too fast. So you are a product of a fast
dynamic world and you have to be fast and dynamic.
Understand. So, so that's
how it is is that you have to reevaluate directions every year, and that's what I do.
That's what we do. Every year we look at what is
hot and we work on those areas. And this is true for academics and
true for industries as well, right?
Next it's like #9. It has been a long time since
auto driving has been invented, but people like us. It still seemed far away from it.
Why is it not so common everywhere in the world? What are the limitations of that?
Will it be possible to be to be to manifest
to be the manufacturer or something else?
Well, the new technologies just don't require only inventors. OK,
after the inventors you need the engineers. After the New Years you need the
market years after the market years. You need people who can make them, who can manufacture them,
who can sell them and and the biggest
of all the customers who need them.
And any of those can be a bottleneck. Particularly the customer if they don't
need it, you and you still want to sell it, then you have to show them what is the trade off?
What is it that they gain that they buy? Putting that money into your thing?
Right, and so every technology goes through that battle.
And some die, some survive, some come come back after 50 years.
I will tell you what this whole photophone the one that you are using right now.
This photo phone was discovered 30 years ago. AT&T offered this service.
You could see your friends on the phone.
30 years ago, but did anybody say no? They gave us $30 a minute.
And so so the idea is that the cost has to come down. The manufacturing has to come down,
volume production has to happen, then the technology comes back. Comes in.
That's a very generic term thing, right? Now I'll tell you what is virtualization,
so I have given lectures in these classes 95. I gave a lecture and running
Internet came in and I said look the Internet is charging virtualization.
We will have virtualized started my virtual classes in 1995. I still have recording on my website.
[no speech detected]
1695 is 21 + 36 years ago. As soon as the Internet started transmitting video, I transmitted it.
Right, but the idea is only saying of
virtual and we're saying and we were seeing we put 4C and we could say that OK,
everything will be virtual is happening. Will be virtual education really
virtual blah blah blah blah, but nothing happened for 35 years until the COVID came in.
Now it's not a question, basically it's in a city.
It's a necessity now,
and so now everybody is virtual.
[no speech detected]
Alright, and I will share your secret. Right now in my family we have
covered right and we are all triple boosted and everything else. I'm not one of those who don't
believe in vaccination etc. But we still got it. But I am giving the classes.
There is no problem. This was not possible. If it was a physical class.
[no speech detected]
Right, so virtualization has its virtues, its necessities, and the
technologies may come or come later, or come whenever they are needed
and and the cost effectiveness is the one of the things right now. Virtually virtual is so cheap.
I mean, last year I attended at least 3040 conferences, I gave a talk at 30-40 conferences.
International conferences. I spoke in Moscow. I spoke in China. I spoke in India.
I spoke so many countries, but didn't go anywhere from my room.
This was not possible before that people said, oh, you can't have a conference.
You know which is virtual. But virtual conferences are free cheap. And very wide ranging,
so we are the sellers of the virtual. We are networking eyes.
We are the start of the virtual we we started virtualization. We believe in virtual.
[no speech detected]
OK. Alright, so how long do you think it takes from a new theory to manufacturing which can be used
around most people worldwide? For example 6G? Well, I told you the whole list,
necessity and cost are often the bottleneck or the obstacles. If if people don't feel necessary they
will not take it and the cost is not zero, it they won't take it. I mean it.
Basically it doesn't have to be 0 but it cannot be more than
what they pay today. In fact, when we were doing Ethernet.
And I was one of the people in the team which was inventing which was
designing Ethernet back in 1980. At digital equipment and they told
us in mantra they said OK if you want to provide if you want to have
something new you should provide 10 times the speed for two times the cost.
That was the mantra that I started when I was myself learning and student,
and you know, really starting out after my PhD. So 10 times the cost.
So we already had 10 Mbit Ethernet and we were designing 100 Mbit Ethernet.
It's 100 Mbit, Ethernet cannot be 10 times if it is 10 * 10 Mbit,
people will not buy it. They would rather buy 20 Mbit
and then 30 Mbit and 40 Mbit. Why would they buy 1000 Mbit?
Right so. That was the mantra was given that the cost has to be so less
basically two times for 10 means. Now people are going to say why they twice just buy the 1000
megabit and we're done with it.
Right, and so that is not a general mantra, but basically cost is the main thing.
If the cost is such that they are going to save money, a lot of money,
then they will come running after you.
[no speech detected]
Page down. Slide number 11 and I'm going fast because you guys have asked lots of questions
and you will see the right away. The benefit of flipping the class.
None of this discussion would have been possible in a unflipped class.
In the unflipped class we hardly cover the words on this slide.
OK, and people are so passive that they will not ask any questions.
[no speech detected]
Alright, so slide #11 is being a smart device, a prerequisite to being an intelligent device.
No, those are two different rates. Intelligence means AI,
smart means network.
And you could have all four possible combinations 00011011.
OK, you could have devices. They are neither smart.
Not intelligent, those are most of the things that we used ten years ago.
You could have devices that are smart. Those are all the things that I have around me.
Everything in my house almost everything is smart, including the can, the fan,
the lighting, the cameras, the whatever you name it. They make it. I have it.
[no speech detected]
OK, intelligence is coming in. Intelligence is coming in my
thermostat says it is intelligent. Hopefully it is and so it it regulates
the temperature. Automatically. Depending upon where I am.
If I go to a different room, it makes the temperature there better
and then here another so intelligence Ji.
OK, does this shift from smart, intelligent, require any additional improvement in networking?
Well, it is both ways. Basically, networking is also becoming intelligent,
so all the devices like your routers, your phone and whatnot, they are and any networking.
In general, the data centers they're adopting AI. We are working on those things now.
Security is making AI. So we are adopting. We are adopting the latest to become
the latest to keep up the latest. And this is like I said,
if you don't adapt you die. Same thing happens with technology.
If the technology doesn't adopt it dies.
It failed if it doesn't adapt, it dies.
OK, so the networking field right now, lot of research and all the researchers
actually that I know of are working on AI.
Adopting AI to networking
and of course networking. Now The thing is, you can do AI. So next question was
somewhere I think here can. Yeah right up there you can have AI without networking.
I have computer which can just do all my AI work without connecting to the Internet.
But basically all this. I mean in this day and age I can't think of my doing anything
without being connected much.
It is down. Do you ever foresee soldiers fighting in these soldiers fighting in the battlefield,
being obsolete, and warfare fought entirely remotely by drones, missile, cyber warfare, etc?
Well, it is happening now. What do you think Russia is doing in Ukraine?
[no speech detected]
While they have they have they have the military people standing by,
but they are already attacking the network.
They already had a network attack last week. And what is happening between China between,
let's say India and Pakistan every day the same thing the war is fought not on the battlefield.
Well on the battlefield too, but mostly on the Internet. What do you think Russia did in
the last election election before? They're not going to. They don't need even money
to change the world. They can just change the world by Internet.
[no speech detected]
Right, so the Internet is the most. Potent weapon if you want
to use it. In that way.
OK, so the hackers,
do you think hackers will become more prevalent as a smart technologies,
computing etc. Become widely used? What steps can be our companies would
take to prevent this in the future? So let me just tell you hackers are not bad people.
Hackers are really intelligent people. You can't be a hacker if you're not intelligent.
There are probably more intelligence, most intelligent people in this society.
The word hacker sounds negative, but it is not. Hackers could be called inventor and
if you wanted to call them that way. And so the hacker are the people
who try things that normal people will not even do or try, right?
So they they they they find out the weakness and they try to see what weaknesses.
Now there are what we call good hackers and bad hackers. Bad hackers will generally
use it for their advantage, but the good hackers will use it for the advantage of this society.
So giving in that conference that we are talking about, I went there. That is where they showed me.
They showed me. Actually these people were from Saint Louis. They showed us in the conference
how to break in a car.
5 miles away. Now, is that good or bad? That's good, because now the
cars people have to be careful. And 1st, the car people deny the
car manufacturer denied they don't. There is no such thing and then later on they fixed it.
So The thing is, and these people didn't make any money out of it. They are good people.
Why would they talk in a conference when they such weaknesses, if they wanted to make money,
they would just go and stop the car and add the money and then take the money and get out.
So Hacker word is not bad. Hacker simply means intelligent, smart,
whatever you want to call them inventive, they try to find the weakness and they
bring out and then then the world changes. So do your personal use.
A lot of smart devices. I have met people who work in the security space who will not
use them due to the possibility of these attacks occurring well. I am an early adopter.
I use things when the day,
I can get lay my hands on them. But use technology wisely
to avoid security pitfalls. So let me tell you what I don't use.
So for example, cloud based things are used only when necessary.
So I have cameras in my house that required. Everything that is going on
around one mile of my house, every single inch however. There is an option in every camera
to record it in the in their cloud. That's a privacy hazard.
[no speech detected]
Right and so other than one or two cameras and one or two cameras which
are pointing in the right direction, I don't record on the cloud because
I don't want that privacy violation. But I use the camera.
And I use only those cameras that offer me both options and option to reuse without the cloud.
Right local storage. Similarly.
Microsoft Office 365. I don't use 365. I use Microsoft Office, which is permanently
installed on my computer, and every option that says we can help you with this.
We can help you with that. We can help you with that. I just turn it off because I don't
want all my words to go to Microsoft. And then analyze there.
And then we told that you did this wrong. This this right? OK,
everything I do on my computer is actually being analyzed by thousand other companies 'cause
there are everybody analyzing it. Google is analyzing it. Apple is analyzing it,
Microsoft is analyzing it. Everybody knows that yesterday I bought a dishwasher.
Right, everybody knows. And then what happens is when I go to someplace,
I just get the ads related to whatever I bought or something related to that.
So right now. Basically I want
to minimize that kind of effect. Hello so I it's not that I
don't use the cloud but I use cloud wherever necessary. If there's a non cloud option and
it is equally good I will use that. So if local computing is an option, why do I do cloud computing?
I will do cloud computing too when it is not an option.
Alright, now I think I'm going to fast. There are no questions, right?
So I'm just continuing and we have plenty to discuss. Slide 15 wow.
How is the hackers conference not illegal? If hackers are informed on the
waste in which to cause corruption? Well, these are the conferences to learn.
I go there in these conferences. They talk about weaknesses in the current
world and it is suitable for the society. It is good for the society.
And have you ever had anything for fun?
We teach hacking in our networking security course. Give you an example why I students,
one of my my students do some project work and one of the projects they did was to develop a.
To develop a develop a system in which they will just put their laptop
near whatever your favorite coffee shop is and and then people will
connect to the free public Internet.
[no speech detected]
Right, and then when they connect they will pass it on to the real public Internet,
except unless it is going to Bank of X, ** if ghost Bent Bank of X ** they could
just produce take you to a fake website. And collect your password and say
sorry the system is down right now.
Is it legal? No, it's not legal. I don't think if they put it somewhere they will go into jail,
but is it OK to practice it? Yes. Now what is the purpose of practicing it?
Because now you know that you should never connect to free public Internet.
[no speech detected]
You got it. And this is what I want to see.
The face is shaking. Alright,
and I don't see much shakings I don't know.
But basically this is hacking is not bad, it's just if you bad
application I feel like guns. Guns are not bad and I don't own any guns. Guns are not bad,
but if you use the gun for something which is wrong then it is bad.
Right clothes are not bad, but if you use clothes for something that is wrong then it is bad.
This applies to everything. Just curious, what topic did you participate at?
The conference is actually the conference was overbooked, overflowing. He has that packed.
I was not able to get into most of the rooms I wanted to get in. You have to go into the you have
to attend one room and then come back and stand in the queue for the next one next hour.
So one hour in the Q one hour inside. That's all we did.
Can you teach us how to hack the cloud in the network security chapter?
Not this chapter, but they take the network security course.
Yes, this course is very condensed.
There's a lot to talk about, just without.
You know, just fundamentals. In the US, the government, CIA, and Afghan,
etc use as the to hire top hackers. Yes, and they were there. They were giving out $2,000,000 if
you because in this conference, by the way you are not required to
put your tell your name to register. You can register by cash only and you get
a badge which does not have your name.
And so nobody knows who is who. Right, I think you saw that in
the video so so the idea is when the CIA wants to know their names.
They put this $2,000,000 and this thing and then people register for that
competition and then they get a job offer.
OK, of course, if you are.
If you are really being bonded on The Wanted list then they will also
take you to jail right there and this will happen for some people. So basically it both ways.
If you are known to be bad then they will take you right there.
Out of curiosity, how vulnerable do you think voting machines are given the current controversies?
I think voting machines are more secure than manual voting. Now this is a very political topic,
but in the manual voting if somebody took a thousand votes and threw them in the garbage,
how will you find out?
Somebody sent you the wrong room and you put your word there.
How did you find out?
Right manual voting has lot more holes than automated voting. Alright,
and the automated voting like anything else that is becoming secure and secure
and secure and that's why they use it now. Alright, but I'm not going to go there,
but basically that's the idea. Is that technology, I believe more in technology than in humans.
Similarly for auto driving the day auto driving car, I can approve. I can I can I can?
Let's see what I can say. I can basically buy. I would buy it and rather than
taking my chances and I don't believe in my driving, I would let it drive.
And you don't know that,
but most of the planes that you are flying are being driven automatically.
They're all on the autopilot.
Right, so machines doesn't mean they're bad. Actually, they don't have tempers.
They don't go to sleep, they don't, I mean. You know they do malfunction,
so you have to worry about redundancy and other things. But human people have more malfunction.
Alright, what is this? Well,
we learn more in depth about cloud computing using this class now.
If you take 570 recent advances in networking, maybe a little more.
OK, so there are many courses after this with more detail. Will you provided?
I'm not sure about the relationship between cloud computing and the Internet.
Well, you can't reach a cloud without the Internet. Period, how will you get the beach
ucloud without the Internet?
Right? And so that's the end, that one.
Next month SDN that SDN power.
Newer networking technologies E5G6G? If so, are the traditional network
non becoming less relevant? The answer is yes slowly.
So he has 5G uses as D N6G is not here, but it will use as of course it
will use as the end and the older technologies are slowly going away.
For example, have you heard of 1G? It doesn't exist anymore.
There was one year I used 1G. I was there when 1G came out. I took at the very first day,
so 1G is there, but we don't use
it not but 2G is still here. 2G is still here in all worldwide. That is the common denominator.
Even if you go to Africa and South in any other place, 2G is there.
OK, they're not died,
and it's very unlikely to die. But Bungie has gone.
Is this software defined networking decentralized and who is responsible for managing all
these connections so SVN is not designed by actually the opposite? SDN is centralized.
And the network manager is responsible for managing the entire network,
so there is this one person sitting here.
Here she is controlling the whole network. And that is the beauty of SDM that
one person can control 2000 devices.
[no speech detected]
OK, so and that's why the SDN came in because the managing these large
networks was becoming very difficult.
Maybe there's DN. Everything is centralized.
Since everyone is sharing the same hardware, would there be any any constraint or
what will happen if the workload of all the network users exceeds the capacity
of the hardware they are sharing? Well, this is true for any sharing when
there is more load, there's overload. There is low service and there are crashes.
This is even true for even not sharing. When I use my computer like this zoom right now.
And I have most powerful computers that I can buy, right? Probably Noble prize, of course,
and it crashes if I overload.
[no speech detected]
Next how would you define a good networking architecture?
If it is good, they will come for it. If it is good, it will be adopted,
period. That is the definition of goodness of anything. If it is good, somebody will say,
yeah, this is good and then and you will see more than yourself using it.
[no speech detected]
In the core is the course more theoretical or applicational? Could you explain more about what the
course is designed to help us to do? Will it help us build design better computer programs?
So answer is this is a system's course.
OK, so it says CC-473 S. That letter South after the
course number is for systems.
OK, and these systems include
both software and hardware. And so it is not a software course
or a hardware course or a theory. Course theory courses are designated with a key.
OK, it will help you efficiently
use networks in your field, including programming. So if you are doing even program,
you have simply interested in programming, you would be able to do more
programming after knowing networking, because now you can program.
Things that can run on two computers. At the same time, our
communicate between them. OK, so this is and and the problem is
that we're not teaching programming. We're not teaching, actually.
Applications things like that. What we're doing is we're telling you how
the thing works so you use Web every day, but you don't know how it works. Use email every day,
but you don't really know how it works. Right and you are using zoom right now,
but you don't know how it works, right? So what we do is we explain to you what is
required for things to make work and what is required to make video go through it.
What is required? You know why you know we didn't have all this before? What new features came in?
What enabled what? So all that knowledge is in this course.
[no speech detected]
Next question. Is it valuable to design a new, better email system?
Will NSF support such kind of projects? Well, this is a normal question for anything, not just NSF,
you have to show the need and the cost to benefit tradeoff of any idea you want to sell to anyone.
OK, if the person on the other
side believes that they will get more than what they are putting in.
They will put their money in.
And this is true for NSF 2. OK, NSF is not there to just waste money or the government
money or people money. They really look for. What is the benefit of this?
How does this society benefit from here?
So everything is. Cash to benefit.
When should we have the textbook by today? Basically, we'll need it today because
the homework that is being assigned today requires you to read chapter one.
OK, of course you will not get
it today from Amazon or from wherever or from book store. You can go to the bookstore
and pick it up today, but you can also order over mail order or whatever and
you will need it because the homework is due on Sunday. So by Sunday. Well,
Sunday is only video review is due. So I mean if you don't have the book,
you can still use the video, but I think it's good to read the book after viewing the video
or while viewing the video, because there is a lot more material in the book than in the
video and you might have some questions which are not in the video but are in the in the book.
[no speech detected]
So it is OK to ask any question anytime. Anytime and right now I'm giving a
monologue because nobody asking any questions and I'm looking at the chat box.
Yeah, go ahead, we can see two questions in the chat box in the chat box against you questions,
so my chat box is missing something. Now let me see. Oh my chat box,
I haven't I know what is missing. I won't scroll it. I have to scroll it to go
down to the latest question. Alright.
Thank you and by the way, for all the students, honey is my league TA.
There are four or five days on this course, so I mean, is keeping track of all this?
Let's see. I will come back to this question. Let me finish this start here about the book.
OK is it digital copy of the test textbook sufficient and OK.
So I don't recommend any illegal copies. Please, I'm an author and there are
people who wrote the book, their authors, and I'm just like you want to steal.
You don't want somebody to steal your thing. The authors don't want somebody steal their thing.
And so as long as you get a legal copy and you can buy a legal copy from from the publisher,
publisher is selling, you know. Soft copies.
At access our rental,
all kinds of things are possible. OK, but it's it's your own
ethics that dictates that.
OK, how unethical you want to be, but that's your choice.
[no speech detected]
When we return to in person class, we still required to watch videos before coming to the lecture.
Instead of reading the text well, it's not instead of. The video is not a substitute
for reading the text. Both are required. You need to read the text please.
You need to watch the video now. The video has a deadline of midnight.
That doesn't mean that your thing starts at midnight stops at midnight. You should really read.
Watch the video much before the midnight. You should read the text and then
log all the questions both from the text and from the book until you
are sure that you understand enough. If not, you should read the textbook after the Q&A session.
So we'll have Q&A session in which we have discussed every
line with a very fine detail. Right and then you might have a question when you read the textbook,
please do, because without reading the textbook, there's no substitute for that.
You have to read the textbook. Alright, the textbook is 800 pages long.
Videos probably will make for 80 pages total.
OK, so it's only a summary of what is in
the book and you have to read the book. So video is providing overview of the text.
OK, so this is about the system bus, prerequisite system bus.
So I have learned the term system bus in a computer systems course,
but it was used to describe the transferring of data between the CPU and memory.
So how would it be connected to networking? Well, you're doing the same thing.
Networking is also an IO device, and so you read and write data to the network devices just
like you write it to memory. OK, so you write something into the
memory and then you read it back or you reading from the memory and
write it back in different locations, same location, same thing.
Networking networking is just another device.
OK, so you can read it from memorial and write it to the network or read that,
read it from the network, write it to the memory and either way I
mean lot of things are happening there. You read it from memory, put into the disk.
Disk is another IO device. They're all on the system bus.
[no speech detected]
Milligram papers in the past few years we provided before the exams, no.
The answer is no. We will provide you the whole review and all that.
You will have an idea of what the exams are like, but we don't provide
these solutions in writing and we don't provide any exams in writing.
Would we have in person classes after the first two weeks are totally online?
The exams will be in person, so right now the plan is to have exams in person. And so on.
The day of exam you will all come to Lopata 101. Sit down next to each other.
And and take your chances. But basically, and the reason is last year we
had exam online and the exam online is responders and it works beautifully and there's no problem
with it except that you know you really have to get a good camera. You really have to get a camera
which is not on your laptop because you know right now even right now
it really better that if you have a camera which is not on your laptop. For example,
right now my camera is not on the laptop. So now my camera is facing the right
angle wherever it's supposed to and my screen is in the right angle that I need to,
otherwise I have to adjust the screen up and down so that I can be visible at the same time.
I can read this screen. So the two things in one place sometimes are not very good, so and
the cameras don't cost anything right now, the cameras are available for $15.
I just checked $9.99 on Amazon. So the cameras are not very expensive,
and in fact the companies that I recommended. I mean, there's no need,
but right now they recommend is Logitech. I use logic tech cameras and they
have been around for 40 years. They have the brand name. And and one of the good Logitech
cameras is for $22.95. I mean, what else can you want so so The thing is,
these things have come down significantly. When I was when I started at that time,
the camera just $95 a $100. In fact, the camera that I'm using right now.
I just got it for $149 this year. So so so there are better cameras
and just to get by cameras, it's about $15 or $10 is not bad, but anyway.
Right now there is no plan to have exams online.
Exams will be in person, but other than that I think
virtual is better. Do I need to read all contents of
chapter one through 8 in the textbook, even if some of the content don't
let them this slide, in other words, does the exam only test the knowledge in
the slides or book content may be tested. So in these slides we have clearly
identified the sections that you're supposed to read in the book.
There are many sections that we have not. We will not cover and you don't have to read them.
[no speech detected]
OK, but if you need to read them, you'll be told.
So it is not the whole book. It is part of the book The Essential
part of the book, and that will be clearly identified in the slides. If it is not clear,
you can ask a question. Alright, let me come back to your question here.
Actually I am also looking at my clock and I have two things to do to finish all the questions that
have been asked and then come back to the chat questions. So I'm going to come back in
a minute to chat questions. Actually I have 26. I have more slides to go in there.
OK, so let's see alright grading. Can you explain how the class participation works?
Well, class participation means answering questions. If I ask a question, you answer.
Attendance if you're not there, you're not gonna get last class participation and remember,
your attendance is not only being taken by zoom, it is also count. It is also monitoring what
you are doing while zooming.
Right, if you are busy on the other screen watching a movie or doing something else,
it monitors that and it lets me know that this person was not paying any attention.
[no speech detected]
And I don't. Question, yeah, so like. During a lecture like,
particularly in Zoom Lecture, I like ask and answer questions like or
I'll get information for something that I'm like wondering about from the Internet,
or I'll drop down my notes in my notepad on my computer.
How does that factor in with? That will be counted and not paying attention. I'll tell you what.
Basically I mean it's it is basically saying that what other things are going on,
where your mouse is. OK, and so it does not know that you are doing productive work that
you're doing for the course work, or you're doing something else.
Are you at chatting with your friends? It cannot distinguish between the
Facebook and the networking course. OK OK alright how many homework left do we have?
We have 26 homeworks and 12 labs. How long do you expect them take all the homeworks are short.
This will not take more than five minutes, but to do that 5 minutes you need five hours of reading.
And I'm just kidding. So you have to read if you know the
homeworks are very simple few lines. They're not very long.
But you have to know the material. And labs require programming and
that they may take some time. OK.
And is there a great distribution scheme? I don't know what that means,
but you get the points for the method and the result half points half
of the points are for the method. If your result is wrong, but the method is right,
you still get half points. And if your method is if your result is right, but you don't,
it didn't show the method or we don't know how you got it or you the wrong way. You got half point.
The PowerPoint says that the negative rating
on incorrect multiple choice questions grade plus one for correct minus one 4
- 1 upon north minus one for incorrect. What does the number N mean?
Is the number number of selections? Yes, N is the number of choices in a multiple choice question.
For example, and is 2 for true and false. So if you take it true and false,
you get half point minus one.
For incorrect and plus one for correct.
So you cannot just randomly mark. If you Mark randomly, you will get a 0.
Do exams involve programming? No.
Can we work in Group? Can you work in the groups of two and three for the labs?
All labs are very short programming or data analysis exercises,
so in some cases you are analyzing a trace.
In the other cases you are. Basically, writing a small program
it's not really worth you know, for two or three people to be doing that.
How in depth is the programming? Does it go down to the programming
protocols are using so if you want to look at the labs and homeworks
you can just go back to the previous years lectures and find them.
We do change the exercises to the numbers are
not the same but you can find them online.
All ears lectures including 2005, 678-910-1320 whatever 21st are
all online on my website. OK, so you can see preview them.
Find out what kind of exercises are labs, those are. OK. What programming language
do we need to learn in order to finish the lab C and Python?
And I know there are people who know only one or the other,
and so I just wanted to tell you beforehand. OK.
Can we see the homework template to clarify the requirements,
see the previous years? I'm using if using the code in the homework, that's the whole code needs
to be included as well, yes? What format do the homeworks take, either in free responses and
multiple choice or true and false? None of the above is calculations. OK, you just do.
You just compute some things and submit the answers.
So how will the solutions to the homework be posted? Well, when neither I will discuss
this solutions in the class. We never post any solutions because the minute you post the solution
it becomes out of date because everybody has gotten default right
and these courses are taken by 2000. Other people who are not in this class. Not for money,
I just make it available for free, but The thing is,
if and many professors use the same lectures. So we don't publish the solutions,
but if you if you need, you can basically and what I do I monitor to.
If So what we do is if there is a homework for which most people got it right.
That's fine if if some if if the variation is very large, that means a lot of people didn't get it.
This at that. Then we discussed that in the class and and and you will know
what is the right way to do it. But then I posted. If this semester switches
to in person instruction, this is the same question.
Will some knowledge only appear in the textbook and not be covered by the lectures?
I think we already covered that. Problems even understanding problem 7.
So problem 7 is about sine Theta.
Well, you need to turn entry for this course. If you don't know, sign and cast sorry
you should drop the course right away because you need to know sine Theta
and that's why the question is here. You need to know binary representation.
You need to know what is CPU. You need to know all this.
OK, what every video have such quizzes beside the video embedded quizzes? The answer is no.
This is only a prerequisite and I put it there so that people can decide.
I mean everything sounds interesting but you need to have background otherwise you will find yourself
behind the queue and then you will complain at the last minute. Hey I, I didn't understand that.
I didn't understand that, but I understand that you need to have some basic things about computing.
This cannot be your first computing course. OK, this is not 131.
Are you required to finish it and upload it to somewhere?
No, this quiz is just for yourself. I would suggest that you take it.
I will provide the answers next time. I will provide the answers next
time you compare your answers. And if you find that you get minus 5.
Just you know, basically think about not continuing the course.
OK, so you set your own threshold. And decide this is help you decide
whether you have the background.
[no speech detected]
When we return to in person classes, will logistic change? No if we were able to start
in person classes in February. Same question, no. Next I have in person classes
right before this and after this class would it be ideal for me to
watch the video recording later on? I don't see what is the problem here
because conditions are mandatory. You have to be here and many students
join the classes from cafeteria. They're sitting right in the cafeteria.
You know, just watching whatever some people go to an empty classroom.
Some people just go to empty space, and if nothing else, you can go to the part of 101. It's empty.
OK, so it doesn't take any seconds
more than what in person class would you you would be doing.
The in person class you cannot attend. Then of course you should not attend this,
but this is not an excuse. You have to be here for discussion because
this is where the learning takes place. Let me tell you everybody has seen the video.
That is the thing that I repeat every year right and every same thing. I say same words right?
And nobody asks any questions but they never got to details.
With this one you get to 10 times more detail into the topic. Then you would be possible
in in unflipped class. So there are two issues here, which are which are not same
unflipped and in person unflipped has nothing to do with the in person.
Even many courses are done flipped.
Even if they're in person. In that case, the flipping out generally means that you read the book.
And here what we are doing is we
are identifying the topics we are giving you the lecture video and then the book is already there.
You read the book and then you come back for discussion.
Alright, should we just come up with silly questions if
you normally don't have any? So here thing why did I make one question mandatory?
To be able to understand everything in 80 minute class and not have a question is mainly due to
religiousness and not smartness. You cannot be so smart that you know
everything if you know everything. Why are you here? Why are you
wasting your time taking this course? So even the idea of asking a silly
question is laziness, not smartness. You should really make the best use of time,
your own time, not mine. Current time and the best use of the
opportunities that you are getting. You're getting an opportunity to ask a question.
Ask it if you have a question. If you don't have a question, then maybe once in awhile it's OK.
But then I had I had I had run these classes without the question so people didn't ask any questions.
They just check Mark. Yeah I bought watch the video and they were done.
Then I put the quizzes in there so now they have to watch the video.
At least go to the quizzes and they're done. They don't want to ask anything. Why?
Because they don't know English because they don't want to speak English.
They don't want to write in English. Well, I want to get you to get over that hurdle.
OK, you won't get education well if
you can't even write a question, you cannot ask a question. So don't
don't worry about it silly questions. Alright, I'm basically running time in time,
that's why I'm I'm hurrying up page up. Exams will be in person, yes.
Will you share your industry experience related to some networking topics?
In every lecture you will find a lot of in videos you say we can take the quiz as
many times as you want, but in my case, after I fill in my answer and submit
the quiz just just gone, I don't. I do not know where to do it again. Is that an updated policy?
No, you can review the video anytime. Once you go back and review the video,
your previous grade will be overridden. And if you have watched it once,
you know what are the right answers, because everything is true and false and you can just answer
it right and you will get 100%. Second time, and that's OK with me.
Because basically I want to make sure that you got the you know what the right
answer is and you got to the video. What is your favorite part section module
of this course to teach entire course? Every topic builds on the previous one.
I can't teach you chapter 2 without chapter one and I can't teach you Chapter 9 without Chapter 7,
and then I can't teach you my next course without discourse.
OK so I need you to really follow the whole way through.
Alright, now I'm going to go back to the chat questions. We are one minute beyond time.
If you have to leave, I don't know. 2:15 is the time or 220.
Honey, you know? At anybody knows what time is the Class 220?
I still have 9 minutes. OK, I'm going to go through this. Chat questions.
OK, yeah, sometimes you talk about something in life.
Then in next minute some app recommends similar items to me. Is there any way we can prevent this
while keeping using keep using the app? So the privacy is gone now.
Basically once you use any free app. Any free app and and on my iPhone
have 200 of them use any free app that reason they're free is because they're
making money out of your privacy.
Everybody has to make money. I mean they're not living here just to give you something free.
So when you get a free Google driving like Google driving are you get a
FREE Email from Google are you get a free this or free that everything
has money attached to it and that money comes by selling your privacy.
Alright. And so the only way you can do is you can go back and select the proper options so that
they cannot monitor your location. They cannot monitor this. Whatever is important to you,
they cannot monitor that and then they will decide whether they want to give you the service or not.
What does decentralize Internet even mean that word will come later on when we talk about centralized
same question next question. Somebody gave the answer,
which is that look up Web 3. Does anybody see lecture to
book sections mapping anywhere? Yes, in our class in our class
schedule there is a lecture to lecture to Berea and I will
share that with you right away. So if you.
Come on. Uhm?
[no speech detected]
So if you go to my web page class web page. Then they did chapter mapping to the
class chapter 12345678 and exam 123.
OK, next question on the chat box.
I'm. Will the court meet in person after first? I think this we discussed five times.
Do we need to use both Python And say yes when we will? When will the office hours begin?
This sinister they will. They will begin as soon as I might.
Whole TA Team TA team recruited by the Department department is still
putting people on the on the basically they're putting on the registers.
Let me put it this way so we have the team, but some of the Members are still not here.
And and there are other issues as soon as that that is done,
and hopefully we'll start the start the.
The hours this week. Although I don't know whether you will have that much to do this
week because there is no homework other than watch the video. But next week onwards when there's
a real homework, people will come. OK, and then we will have the DTA hours.
So other than that I'm that. Is it just a comment from before the class,
only 25 phases under video settings you
can select 49 participants you are using up. To the data desktop client of
zoom your PC supports it OK, Alright, thank you for that tip. I will find out that setting.
Let me see if you how do you. How do you. How do you get to 50? Does anybody who wrote this.
Thomas Gibbons. Can you explain where is the option? For 49.
You can chat it or you can sleep. Yeah, if you go to your words
close to where it says stop video, you can hit the arrow,
go to video settings. And then on video, just Scroll down to the bottom.
And there's a maximum participants in the gallery view.
Thank you, thank you, thank you very much. See this is a class participation point right there.
OK, alright, so now I can see 49 videos.
Right this minute I get that. Alright, anything else? I've covered everything.
I still have 5 minutes.
Actually, I had some more things to discuss. Yeah, so let me
just go back to my presentation.
Uhm? Yeah so. Yeah, yeah.
Alright, so after the related modules, there are three slides this time.
And the first is instructions for passing the class video. I already put those so you already have
seen those four and then it slides. It slides everything in. This course is public basically in
the sense that you know everybody else outside the class also knows about it,
so these slides are there. The new slides of today will be put again back under the website,
and when the video is ready, the video is being recorded. It will be put back on the website so you
can see when the Q&A videos if you want to. Alright, next is.
Features so you all you know basically that there's a table of contents
so you can go to a video and you can jump to any slide you want. You don't have to watch the
whole video to go to slide #17. You could just jump to slide #17 there
is a captions you can enable and disable. There is full screen feature so we have
tried to do the latest as much as possible. There is one more page which is not showing up.
Let me see what is happening here.
Yeah, I don't know why this page did not show up. Tell them yeah.
OK, alright, so this is the page, so this is the hype cycle 2021.
This is the latest available from Gardner and by the way we are lucky enough to
have the gardener service in Washoe. If you're a Washoe student or professor,
you can get this for free in other places would be $5000 for
this same piece of information. Listen, make the best use of it.
However, the things that are here right now. Those I mean actually the chart
is not as dense as it was before, so that is makes me unhappy. But then basically, generative AI,
decentralized finance, compressible network, quantum machine learning. So I have marked these areas
basically and this is what I do. Basically I go through these and then
I just want to make sure that I'm not. I'm fully aware of those.
And this is what you have to do too. Right, and and if it's starting point
for that is just that report itself. You can you can go to that report and that
explains in one paragraph each of these you know doesn't spend too much time.
But then you can follow up more by Google, or you know Wikipedia or whatever.
So that was one thing I wanted to put the latest Gartner chart. I still have two minutes.
Any other questions or comments suggestions? Oh Professor, can you explain
what the sine function is? What is sine function is this is a sine function right there.
If I dry horizontal line. String Demetri will teach me the sign function.
Looks almost like this and.
And basically this time function is important for this course because
the whole wireless is a waveform. A sine wave form.
So when you get a 5G2G1G3G. And in fact, even this Ethernet
that is not wireless wired thing. What we do is we send waveforms.
Everything all these signals are wavefronts. So even if you do an off, let's say you have zeros and
ones when you send to the wires, they become a waveform. Their farm is like a wave
that you put a stone. You put a stone on the on the lake and the wave is formed.
That is a sine function. OK, and. Oh yeah, so that is one thing,
but let me just say I have one more thing which OK 220 minutes is done.
But let me let me just try this out. Before you I let you go.
If you have to go you can go but.
Uhm? The. There is an option to ask questions
and I was going to try that out, but I can find it now so more.
More more more more more OK. Well next time. So basically I want to make sure that
people who are not computer networking people this will not be taking computing, computing people.
This will not be taking this course. You really need to be really
very highly computer literate. To be able to take computer networking course,
because we assume this all the time.
OK, and second thing if you are, if you are a first year student maybe
you should not take this course. Maybe you should take it and this is
designed for the 4th year senior students. Right and up. So if you are a senior,
of course this is the right time right place. Even juniors can take it,
but before that, it's kind of, you know, little bit heavy and people were masters and PHD's.
This could be heavy for you because our journey our seniors are very smart. OK, just to warn you,
our undergrads are smarter than our grads. This is a fact, and so you are competing with
a very smart crowd. And so just here to work harder if you are
taking an undergrad course here. Thank you.
Professor, I just have one more question.
How does the sine function relate to the cosine function? Well, he asked in a metro man.
I mean, I, I'm telling you, you really need to finish that up because
I cannot teach you tecnotree here. But the sign and cosine are very related,
and then these squares add up to one. But the idea is that that is a lot of technology.
There's a lot of math there. And and that is starting high school, actually, I never, I.
I don't think you know these even taught in in here at Washoe. Maybe I know people can tell you.
Your colleagues can tell you where they learned about the sign function.
But that is a must.
OK, thank you.
[no speech detected]